

# YASAMAN FARAZAN

GAME PROGRAMMER & DESIGNER ♥ DÜSSELDORF, 40477, GERMANY 📞 +4915205324226

# • DETAILS •

Blücherstr, 17 Düsseldorf, 40477 Germany +4915205324226 y.farazan@gmail.com

> Place of birth Tehran

# ° SKILLS °

**Unity Engine** 

C#

**Unreal Engine** 

C++

Game Maker

**Design Patterns** 

Clean Code

**Rapid Prototyping** 

**Project Management** 

Agile Development

Game Design

Tabletop Game Design

Machinations

**UX** Design

Figma

Adobe Photoshop

Microsoft Office

**Game Balancing** 

2D Animation

Documentation in Notion & Miro

# ° LINKS °

**LinkedIn** 

**Twitter** 

itch.io

<u>Instagram</u>

#### PROFILE

Self-motivated and creative Game Programmer & Designer with 7+ years of experience. Co-founder of an indie team in 2016 with a top-grossing game in the local market. Worked on a team that managed to join the Embracer group. Seeking a game programming or technical game design position to utilize my knowledge and potential for increased responsibility.

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## Game Programmer & Designer at Massive Miniteam, Cologne, Germany

October 2021 — Present

Started as a freelancer and later joined the team as a porting programmer. After showing my knowledge and skill in creative problem solving, I became Technical Game Designer, working with Unreal Engine, and contributing to the team's core project.

#### Unity Programmer at Brainseed Factory, Bonn, Germany

February 2020 — October 2020

Refactored and developed a mobile game project. Worked on an educational 3rd-person adventure game and implemented many primary features of the game like dialogue system, map and navigation, cinematics system, and UI implementation in Unity. At the same time cooperated with the vision holder and improved some design decisions and systems of the game.

# Unity Programmer at ANIMA RES GmbH, Bonn, Germany

April 2019 — July 2019

Worked on successful AR medical solutions, such as Insight Heart, for mobile devices, HoloLens, and Magic leap. I solely developed a usage instruction AR project for a medical device and improved the UX of the product by designing prototypes to pitch my proposals.

#### Co-Founder & Game Designer at Acid Green Games, Tehran, Iran

June 2016 — November 2021

Led and managed a team of six in developing multiple new games, from concept to delivery and maintenance. As one of the co-founders, I was responsible for our projects' overall vision and production while helping with the design and programming. We developed three mobile games over four years and multiple PC prototypes. I improved my knowledge in Live-ops and turned one of our projects into a top-grossing game in the local market that is still selling well.

# Game Programmer & Designer, Tehran - Iran

September 2014 — November 2016

Worked in multiple indie teams, mainly as a Designer, before moving to Germany. One of my achievements during this time was helping find solutions to fuzzy problems by simulating more rapid design systems, like employing an interactive spreadsheet that mimicked the game mechanics to figure out the best balancing solution for the game units. Participated in many competitions and won multiple prizes for digital game development and one for tabletop game design.

#### HOBBIES

Lately, I particularly enjoy playing tabletop games alongside video games. I work on personal passion projects. I have recently begun working on a digital prototype of one of my game ideas on Tabletop Simulator.

# LANGUAGES

Persian

**English** 

German

#### EDUCATION

# Bachelor of Game Programming, Cologne Game Lab, Köln, Germany

September 2017 — August 2021

Graduated with perfect results. My thesis title was "Breaking the Virtual Ice: Toxic Behaviors in Social VRs and How Developers Cope with Them."

# Bachelor of Industrial Design, University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran

January 2011 — January 2016

Graduated with high honors and perfect results. My thesis title was "Integration of AR Technology and Interactive Media in the Tourism Industry," and I achieved the full grade in the B.Sc. dissertation. I designed and developed an AR mobile experience using Unity to prototype my proposal for an exciting solution to introduce the Iranian tourist attractions to people worldwide.

# COURSES

## Game Design, Iran Game Development Institute

2013 - 2014

## Game Animation (Kinematika), Inverse School

November 2019 — November 2019

#### ★ PROJECTS

#### Beethoven: Follow The Music, Creative Director, Programming

August 2019 — December 2019

The project was a part of the BTHVEN 2020 event to celebrate Beethoven's 250th birthday in collaboration with WDR3, a famous German public radio station. WDR selected our game for investment and further development among a dozen other games. Since we wanted an immersive music experience, I designed and actualized the idea as a mobile AR experience. I managed our team of three for about five months, and we didn't miss any deadlines. One of my achievements in this project was designing a level design tool to facilitate our design workflow.

#### GLARS - Dialab, Programmer

March 2018 — February 2019

A learning project for students in the field of training for biological-technical assistants at the Rheinische Akademie Köln gGmbH. My husband and I worked on this project as programmers during our studies. We introduced solutions to some of the implementation problems of the project to facilitate the work of other parties engaged in the development.

# Daberna Online, Game Design, UI/UX Design

May 2017 — November 2021

An Online mobile Bingo game that is still live and running. Daberna is still one of the top-grossing games in the local market, with 200k users. To achieve this, I improved my knowledge in mobile game design and analyzed the game data to enhance the experience and revenue. Our KPIs grew to skyrocket by conducting multiple A/B testing and improving our remote control over the game metrics.

# Live TV Tycoon, Creative Director & Designer

June 2016 — May 2017

Our indie team's first commercial experience was a tycoon mobile game, providing the experience of managing a TV station. As the game designer and creative director, I ensured the project's vision was clear for all team members during different phases of development. I learned and executed agile development for the first time in this project.

# **★** HONORS & AWARDS

#### Mentor and Jury of Casual Camp

October 2020

Casual Camp was a competition with educational goals for entry-level game developers. The event was held by Cafe Bazaar, the most successful Android Market in Iran. Its purpose was to teach newcomers in various disciplines the development skills and process of a casual mobile game. As one of the mentors, I participated in the presentations and provided feedback and support to all team members. For the final selection, I played all projects, ranked them, and prepared a descriptive list of feedback on each game.

### Volunteer Keynote Video Persian Subtitle Translation

January 2018 — January 2020

Translated all keynote videos and diversifies text for two years to Persian for Global Game Jam event.

## Most Innovative PC Game, Tehran Game Convention

July 2018

Tehran Game Convention was a video game conference held by Iran Computer and Video Games Foundation in partnership with Game Connection. One of my student projects, "Woodfarer," won the prize for the most innovative PC game. As the designer and animator of the project, I developed a new battle system for our rogue-like project and designed the level generation logic. The game was also nominated for the best visual design award.

#### Most Innovative Mobile Game, Tehran Game Convention

July 2017

Won the award for the most innovative mobile game development. The game was also nominated for the best mobile game award.

# First Place in Roomiz Tabletop Game Design Competition, Tehran

June 2017

Jamey Stegmaier, the designer of Scythe board game and co-founder of Stonemaier Games, was the final judge of the competition and selected my design for the "Astrolabe" game as the final winner.

#### First Place in University Entrance Exam (Konkur) of Art, Tehran

2011

Achieved first place in the national-wide university entrance exam among twenty thousand other participants.

## ■ REFERENCES

References available upon request